<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ELENA PUPAZA</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>ELENA PUPAZA</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua7fa2617629f8ab3e741f6b0609183be_7102_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>ELENA PUPAZA</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Cost Flights and Far-Right Votes</title>
      <link>/post/transport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/transport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transportation and geography scholars link low-cost flights to a new type of hypermobile migration, but the political implications of this development remain poorly understood. We examine patterns of migration and far-right voting in London following the Eastern enlargement of the European Union in 2004 and 2007. We show that the distribution of migrants from this region is linked to pre-existing transport infrastructure providing access to low-cost flights back home. Combining ward-level election and census data with geo-referenced information on bus stops serving relevant airports, our instrumental variable approach addresses immigrant sorting and reveals a large positive effect on changes in support for far-right anti-immigrant parties between the 2004 and 2012 London elections. Our approach expands the methodological toolkit for studying the effects of migration. The findings challenge claims of low-cost airlines &amp;ldquo;bringing the EU closer together&amp;rdquo; and have policy implications based on the spatial predictability we uncover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/10.1086/724968&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read the full paper!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Educational Inequality among the Children and Grandchildren of Refugees?</title>
      <link>/post/refugees3gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/refugees3gen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent years have seen a global increase in the number of refugees fleeing from persecution at home. Measuring their adaptation in receiving countries is a key first step towards minimizing and preventing inequality. However, it has become apparent that an intergenerational perspective is required in order to fully capture the long-run challenges faced by refugees and their descendants. This paper uses Swedish register data to examine the importance of family structures and parental socio-economic status in the educational attainment of the children and grandchildren of refugees, relative to those with four Swedish-born grandparents. Surprising findings emerge. Not only do we reveal signs of increasing inequality for later generations of refugees’ descendants, but we also show that these inequalities are determined by parental socioeconomic inequality in multiple domains of life. Counter to theoretical expectations, those who are most likely to experience education inequality are the descendants of refugees with mixed—native-born and foreign-born—parents or grandparents. These findings suggest a need for policies that help refugees to obtain levels of socioeconomic status—in education, employment and earnings—that are typical of those in their new destination, not only because this is of benefit to themselves, but also because this is likely to result in considerable benefits for their children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://su.figshare.com/articles/preprint/Persistent_Educational_Inequality_among_the_Children_and_Grandchildren_of_Refugees_/21896496&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read the full paper!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The legacy of exile for children of refugees</title>
      <link>/post/refugeesdomains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/refugeesdomains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While much is known about the lives of refugees, less is known about the lives of their children, particularly with respect to the inequalities that they may face in adulthood. Using longitudinal data for the whole population of Sweden, we study outcomes at age 30 across different domains of life, including: education, earnings, family formation and the receipt of social support for unemployment, housing, or poor health. We make comparisons between Swedish-born children of refugees, Swedish-born children of non-refugee immigrants, Swedish-born children of Swedish-born parents, and foreign-born refugees who arrived as children. We then examine variation by parental country of birth for Swedish-born children of refugees. Our results show that inequalities and disparities are extremely heterogeneous, by outcome, by sex, and by parental background. Despite lower fertility at age 30, Swedish-born children of refugees experience inequalities in earnings, unemployment and housing support. This is true for both women and men, but varies considerably by parental country of birth. Children of refugees from Lebanon or Chile are the most likely to experience disadvantage, in contrast to those with parents from Iran or Poland. Those with two refugee parents fare better than those with one refugee parent and one Swedish-born parent, suggesting that a native-born parent is not necessarily protective against inequality. We find clear evidence of segmented adaptation for the children of refugees, but our findings suggest that adaptation is far from a uniform process, with a much richer picture emerging from a comparison across multiple domains of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://su.figshare.com/articles/preprint/The_legacy_of_exile_for_children_of_refugees_Inequality_and_disparity_across_multiple_domains_of_life/21739436&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read the full paper!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economic Effects of Partner Loss</title>
      <link>/post/suddendeath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/suddendeath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The death of a partner has many consequences, including for the economic lives of those they leave behind. Theories predict that these consequences will not only differ by sex (for women and men in opposite-sex couples, especially those with children) but also by nativity (for immigrants as compared with the native-born), as well as for the intersection between sex and nativity. Here, we test these predictions by estimating the effect of partner death on income and employment. We use register data for the whole population of Sweden and focus on quasirandom partner deaths among opposite-sex couples with children. Our results show that partner death has a negative effect on both income and employment, but more so for men than women. The findings indicate that male immigrants are more negatively affected by partner death than native-born men, especially when the partner who dies is another immigrant. The only subgroup who experience a positive impact are female immigrants who experience the death of an immigrant partner. We discuss these findings, which suggest that work retains a prominent place in the life course of immigrant women after the sudden death of a partner, perhaps due to a lack of support and the necessity of meeting economic constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://su.figshare.com/articles/preprint/Economic_Effects_of_Partner_Loss_Examining_vulnerability_at_the_intersection_of_gender_and_nativity/16691311&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read the full paper!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency and electoral consequences</title>
      <link>/post/accountability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accountability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can voters hold politicians accountable when policies are implemented and information is disseminated with a considerable time lag? This paper focuses on prospective and retrospective evaluations of changes in the State Pension Age (SPA) in the United Kingdom. Combining secure-level panel data from two national household surveys with administrative data, and applying a difference in differences research design, I analyse the variation in political preferences before and after (a) the implementation of the policy and (b) the time when voters receive written notification of the policy change (15 years later). I find that in the immediate aftermath of the reform, affected voters became more disillusioned with politics and slightly more more empathetic towards smaller parties. Surprisingly, the notification treatment has no effect on political preferences although there are still some weak effects on political disillusionment. The findings are of particular relevance to understanding how policy-makers communicate with the public and how the public responds to policies that have long-term implications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naturalisation trends in post-Brexit Britain</title>
      <link>/post/citizenship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/citizenship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With dual citizenship comes not only freedom of movement, but also the right to have a say in national politics. Since migrants are not evenly distributed geographically, the sudden surge in applications for British citizenship in the aftermath of the Brexit referendum could mean that, in certain geographic areas, the median voter profile may match the profile of an immigrant. Thus, if the new citizens become active voters, a new electoral map could emerge; one where urban constituencies become even more salient in politics, and where new political entrepreneurs will start targeting this previously unenfranchised group. Studying the political socialisation trajectories of individuals who join the electorate by naturalisation is a key component in understanding the political behaviour of social change and making better electoral predictions. The paper identifies the most prevalent socio-economic characteristics of successful applicants for British citizenship and connects them with the corresponding voting behaviour literature and administrative data in other to develop hypothesis about their political preferences and their participation in future elections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
