<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elena C. Pupaza and Joachim Wehner | ELENA PUPAZA</title>
    <link>/author/elena-c.-pupaza-and-joachim-wehner/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/elena-c.-pupaza-and-joachim-wehner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Elena C. Pupaza and Joachim Wehner</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua7fa2617629f8ab3e741f6b0609183be_7102_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Elena C. Pupaza and Joachim Wehner</title>
      <link>/author/elena-c.-pupaza-and-joachim-wehner/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Cost Flights and Far-Right Votes</title>
      <link>/post/transport/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/transport/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transportation and geography scholars link low-cost flights to a new type of hypermobile migration, but the political implications of this development remain poorly understood. We examine patterns of migration and far-right voting in London following the Eastern enlargement of the European Union in 2004 and 2007. We show that the distribution of migrants from this region is linked to pre-existing transport infrastructure providing access to low-cost flights back home. Combining ward-level election and census data with geo-referenced information on bus stops serving relevant airports, our instrumental variable approach addresses immigrant sorting and reveals a large positive effect on changes in support for far-right anti-immigrant parties between the 2004 and 2012 London elections. Our approach expands the methodological toolkit for studying the effects of migration. The findings challenge claims of low-cost airlines &amp;ldquo;bringing the EU closer together&amp;rdquo; and have policy implications based on the spatial predictability we uncover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/10.1086/724968&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read the full paper!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
