<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elena C. Pupaza | ELENA PUPAZA</title>
    <link>/author/elena-c.-pupaza/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/elena-c.-pupaza/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Elena C. Pupaza</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua7fa2617629f8ab3e741f6b0609183be_7102_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Elena C. Pupaza</title>
      <link>/author/elena-c.-pupaza/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency and electoral consequences</title>
      <link>/post/accountability/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/accountability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can voters hold politicians accountable when policies are implemented and information is disseminated with a considerable time lag? This paper focuses on prospective and retrospective evaluations of changes in the State Pension Age (SPA) in the United Kingdom. Combining secure-level panel data from two national household surveys with administrative data, and applying a difference in differences research design, I analyse the variation in political preferences before and after (a) the implementation of the policy and (b) the time when voters receive written notification of the policy change (15 years later). I find that in the immediate aftermath of the reform, affected voters became more disillusioned with politics and slightly more more empathetic towards smaller parties. Surprisingly, the notification treatment has no effect on political preferences although there are still some weak effects on political disillusionment. The findings are of particular relevance to understanding how policy-makers communicate with the public and how the public responds to policies that have long-term implications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naturalisation trends in post-Brexit Britain</title>
      <link>/post/citizenship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/citizenship/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With dual citizenship comes not only freedom of movement, but also the right to have a say in national politics. Since migrants are not evenly distributed geographically, the sudden surge in applications for British citizenship in the aftermath of the Brexit referendum could mean that, in certain geographic areas, the median voter profile may match the profile of an immigrant. Thus, if the new citizens become active voters, a new electoral map could emerge; one where urban constituencies become even more salient in politics, and where new political entrepreneurs will start targeting this previously unenfranchised group. Studying the political socialisation trajectories of individuals who join the electorate by naturalisation is a key component in understanding the political behaviour of social change and making better electoral predictions. The paper identifies the most prevalent socio-economic characteristics of successful applicants for British citizenship and connects them with the corresponding voting behaviour literature and administrative data in other to develop hypothesis about their political preferences and their participation in future elections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
